(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
こんねねー！
Kon-nene!
ホロライブ5期生オレンジ担当、
Hololive 5th Gen Orange representative,
みんなの心の、エナジードリンク、
everyone's heart Energy Drink,
桃鈴ねねでーす！
Momosuzu Nene!
さあ、今日はねねの誕生日！イエーイ！
So, today is Nene's birthday! Yay!
みんな、ハッピーバースデーありがとう、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for the happy birthday wishes!
というわけで今日は、
So, today...
ハッシュタグ #桃鈴ねね生誕祭2024 で
using the hashtag #MomosuzuNeneBirthday2024,
たくさんポストしてください！
please post a lot!
今日はこれからですね、
Today from now on,
ねねの大好きなゲームで遊んだりとか、
playing Nene's favorite games,
大好きなみんなと歌ったりとか、
and singing with everyone I love,
いろんなことをやっていきたいと思います！
I want to do various things!
というわけで、ねねとみんなの大冒険、
So, Nene and everyone's great adventure,
いくぞー！
let's go!
ま、歩いていこうかな。
Well, I think I'll walk.
はぁ、やっと着いたぞ。
Phew, finally arrived.
マジ疲れた、歩いてくるの本当に。
I'm seriously tired from walking here, really.
わくわく、わくわく。
Waku waku, waku waku.
入場しちゃうぞ！
I'm entering!
すごい！おー！すごい楽しい！おー！
Wow! Oh! This is so fun! Oh!
オシャレ魔女❤ラブ and ベリー
Fashionable Witch: Love and Berry
これわ！このゲームは！
This! This game is...!
うわー！ラブ and ベリーじゃないか、これ！
Whoa! It's Love and Berry, isn't it?!
フリープレイだよ
It's free play!
ちょっとー！
Wait a sec!
セクシーダンスを踊ってくださ〜い！
Please perform a sexy dance!
というわけで今日は、まつりちゃんとはあちゃまに来てもらいました！
So today, I have Matsuri-chan and Haachama here with me!
やったー！いぇーい！
Yay! Woo-hoo!
そしてはあちゃま、久しぶり！
And Haachama, it's been a while!
ね！久しぶり！
Right! It's been a long time!
久しぶり！ね、そんな時間？
Long time no see! Wow, has it been that long?
久しぶりだよ〜！
It sure has been!
二人はラブベリやったことありますか？
Have you two ever played Love and Berry before?
まつりはね、あります！
I have played it!
おお〜！
Oh~!
あのオシャレ魔女です。
I'm one of those 'Fashion Witches'.
おお、わかってるね！わかってるね！
Oh, you know your stuff! You know your stuff!
はあちゃまは？
How about you, Haachama?
ない！
Never!
やったことない。
I've never done it.
本当に初めて？
Is it really your first time?
本当に初めて！
Really truly my first time!
へぇ〜、初見です。
Yeah, I'm a complete novice.
じゃあまだオシャレ魔女じゃないんだ。
So you're not a Fashion Witch yet.
オシャレ魔女じゃない。
Not a Fashion Witch.
まぁ、そういうことになります。
Well, that's how it is.
今日よろしくお願いします。
Nice to be here today.
はい、というわけで今日ははあちゃまもオシャレ魔女になってもらおうと思うので、
Okay, so today I want Haachama to become a Fashion Witch too,
早速遊んでいきたいと思います！
so let's get right into the game!
ラブベリっていうのはオシャレを自分でコーディネートして、
In Love and Berry, you coordinate your own fashion,
ダンス・リズム・オシャレバトルみたいなのをするんだよね。
and then you do a dance-rhythm-fashion battle.
さあ、それをやるにはまずオシャレ力を上げないといけないんです。
Now, to do that, you first need to raise your fashion power.
なのでそれを研究するモードがあるので、
So there's a research mode for that,
研究？
Research?
それで遊んで、その後に、
we'll play that first, and then,
リズムゲームで遊んでいきたいと思います！
we'll move on to the rhythm game!
というわけで今回は、ねねの私物のカードを用意しましたー！
And for today, I've brought my own personal collection of cards!
桃鈴ねね自前カード
Momosuzu Nene's personal cards
すっごーい！
Whoa, amazing!
マジで凄いじゃん！
That's seriously impressive!
待って待って、ヤバい！
Wait, wait, this is crazy!
本当にヤバい！
It really is!
これ押したら、始まるらしいんですよ。
Apparently, if I press this, it'll start.
カードをとってね♪
Take a card! ♪
え、カード出てきた！
Oh, a card came out!
ああ！マジカルヘア！
Ah! Magical Hair!
これめっちゃレアなやつ！
This is a super rare one!
レアだ！髪の色変えれるんだ！
It's rare! You can change the hair color!
で、まずはこのオシャレ研究モード。
First, let's start with this Fashion Research mode.
この場所に、場所に合わせて基本的にコーディネートするんだ。
Basically, you coordinate based on the location.
時間内でコーディネートできるように練習するモード。
It's a mode to practice coordinating within the time limit.
じゃあまずはねねがお手本でやっていくわ。
Alright, I'll show you how it's done first.
ラッキーカラーは青色です！
The lucky color is blue!
青いドレス、青いドレス！
Blue dress, blue dress!
ほら、こうやってス〜ッて。
See, you just swipe it like this.
ロイヤルターコイズっていうドレス。
This dress is called 'Royal Turquoise'.
ロングアップヘアにして。
Let's go with the 'Long Up' hair.
スキャンすることによって色が変えられるんだ。
You can change the color by scanning it.
そこのバーと、音でわかる。
You can tell by the bar and the sound.
ジュエリーサンダル
Jewelry Sandals
333！凄い！
333! Incredible!
や、アイドルステージと言えばこの衣装みたいなのあるよね。
Yeah, when you think of the Idol Stage, this is the outfit.
アイドルステージ、行くぞ！
Let's go to the Idol Stage!
というわけで、これで一回実際に対戦してみようか！
Alright, let's try an actual battle with this!
そう、リズムだよ！
Exactly, it's all about the rhythm!
町でうわさのラブとベリー
Love and Berry, the talk of the town
ダンスとおしゃれが大好き
They love to dance and dress up
いつも二人はプリッティ
The two of them are always pretty
今日も決めてるチビッティ
Looking sharp today too, little ones
でも大事なことは 見た目じゃなくて
But what matters most isn't how you look
ぶとうかい
Ballroom dance
優しくなくちゃ
You have to be gentle
オシャレしたって ダメダメ
Dressing up is not enough
心に響く
Resonating in the heart
リズムが大事
The rhythm is important
心に響く
Resonating in the heart
言葉が大事
The words are important
街で噂の ラブとベリー
The talk of the town, Love and Berry
今日も二人は ベリーハッピー
Today too, the two are Berry Happy
明日は二人で お買い物
Tomorrow, the two go shopping
渋谷のワンコが 待っている
The dog in Shibuya is waiting
アイドルステージ！
Idol Stage!
びっくりしたー！
That surprised me!
えー、よくね？
Eh, wasn't that cool?
光ったと思ったら...
I thought it flashed, then...
ねぇたち、世界に入っちゃってたじゃん、今の。
We were inside the world just now.
てか、はあとちゃん、完璧に踊ってた。
But Haato-chan, you danced perfectly.
すごかった！ 初見じゃないか！
It was amazing! Like you've done it before!
何やるって言うから、練習してきたんだよ。
Since you told me what we'd do, I practiced.
大変だったよね、練習。
Practice was tough, wasn't it?
頑張ったよね。
You worked hard.
じゃあここで、魔女として一歩進んできたねねたち、
So now, we who have stepped up as witches,
総当たり戦で、優勝者決めていきたいと思います。
will decide the winner through a round-robin tournament.
なるほど！
I see!
オシャレ魔女対決！
Fashionable Witch Showdown!
はあとちゃんとまつりちゃん。
Haato-chan and Matsuri-chan.
まつり行く？
Matsuri, you going?
オッケー！
Okay!
まつり vs はあと
Matsuri vs Haato
ピンクだ！急げ！
It's pink! Hurry!
服はこれ、ど定番。
The clothes will be this, the classic.
キューティーピンクドレス
Cutie Pink Dress
いきなり来ちゃうんじゃない？これ。
Isn't this coming on strong?
まつりちゃんぽい！
So Matsuri-chan-like!
ベリーの定番、ラブの定番なのだ。
Berry's classic, Love's classic.
ピンクリボンヒール
Pink Ribbon Heels
お姫様ヘア。
Princess hair.
おひめさまヘア
Princess Hair
見て、お姫様ヘア。あ、もう定番だね。
Look, princess hair. Ah, it's a classic.
ミラクルファンデーション。
Miracle Foundation.
ミラクルファンデーション
Miracle Foundation
オシャレしないと。とりあえずすごい。
Gotta dress up. Anyway, it's amazing.
はあとちゃんは緑！
Haato-chan is green!
緑あさな...な、な、な。
Green asana... na, na, na.
これだ！
This one!
ここにDって書いて...、これドレスのDだ。
It has a D written here... it's D for Dress.
靴、こっちの方が合う気がするけど、色変えれるんだよ。
I feel like these shoes match better, but you can change the color.
もう、持ちきれないや。
I can't hold any more.
ミラクルドレス。これも定番感あるよね。
Miracle Dress. This also feels classic.
ミラクルドレス
Miracle Dress
まだスリッパだよ。やばいやばい。
She's still in slippers. Oh no.
グリーンティンカーヒール。
Green Tinker Heels.
グリーンティンカーヒール
Green Tinker Heels
これ使って色変えたら？
How about using this to change colors?
ジュエリーサンダル！
Jewelry Sandals!
ジュエリーサンダル
Jewelry Sandals
ミラクルフットカラー。
Miracle Foot Color.
ミラクルフットカラー
Miracle Foot Color
オシャレパワー！
Fashion power!
357！
357!
315！
315!
髪型お揃いじゃん。
Our hairstyles are the same.
初めて聞いた、これ。やばい、やばい。
This is my first time hearing this. Oh no.
パジャマじゃん！
That's pajamas!
まつりちゃんの真似するわ。
I'll copy Matsuri-chan.
え、ずっとタンプしてるだけ？
Eh, are you just tapping all the time?
初見殺しだ！
It's a first-timer killer!
パジャマが効いてない！
The pajamas aren't working!
初見じゃないって言ったのに！
Even though I said I'm not a first-timer!
初見の曲、リズムきついって！
This first-timer song's rhythm is tough!
けっか発表！
Result announcement!
まつりちゃんやったー！
Matsuri-chan did it!
823点です！
It's 823 points!
めっちゃやったからね、このステージ。
I've played this stage so many times.
はーーっ！
Haaaa!
いくぞー！
Let's go!
アイドルステージ はあと vs ねね
Idol Stage: Haato vs Nene
かわ…ソックス…
Cute... socks...
えっと…これ！
Uh... this!
245！
245!
かわいい！どう？
Cute! How's this?
271！
271!
でもラッキーが回れない…
But I'm not getting Lucky symbols...
大丈夫！ベリーの方が…
It's okay! Berry's...
やばい、この曲も知らん！
Oh no, I don't know this song either!
懐かしい！
Nostalgic!
ちょっと待って…！
Wait a second...!
やばい、曲が聴こえない！
Oh no, I can't hear the song!
自分の声で！
Because of our own voices!
自分の声で曲が…
Because of our own voices, the song is...
逆にそれで妨害するしかないのかも知れない…
Maybe we just have to use that to interfere with each other...
めっちゃ作ってるやん！
You're really getting into it!
わい！あ、パジャマウォーリア…！
Yay! Ah, Pajama Warrior...!
あ！パジャマウォーリア待て！パジャマウォーリア待て！
Ah! Wait, Pajama Warrior! Wait, Pajama Warrior!
いけいけ！あー！
Go, go! Ah!
ということで、今の勝負は…
So, for that battle...
何か割と目茶苦茶でしたが、ねねの勝ち！
It was kind of a mess, but Nene wins!
音何も聴こえなかった本当に！
I really couldn't hear a thing!
じゃあ、最強決めちゃう？
Then, shall we decide who's the strongest?
決めちゃおうか！
Let's do it!
最強決めちゃおうか！
Let's decide the strongest!
ストリートコート ねね vs まつり
Street Court: Nene vs Matsuri
決まった！275！すごい！
It's set! 275! Amazing!
でも二重丸ラッキー二重丸だ！
But I got double-circle Lucky symbols!
おー！ほら！ラッキー花びら！おー！
Oh! Look! Lucky petals! Oh!
おー来た！最初からボーナスタイム！
Oh, it's here! Bonus time right from the start!
あ！いいんじゃない？
Ah! Isn't this good?
いいんじゃない？いいんじゃない？
Isn't it good? Isn't it good?
いいんじゃない？
Isn't it good?
格好いい！
Cool!
オッケー！
Okay!
いいね、いいね！
Nice, nice!
うわ！格好いい！決まった！
Whoa! Cool! Perfect!
やった！あー！でもまつりすごい！
Yay! Ah! But Matsuri was amazing!
いい勝負だったな！
That was a good match!
はい！最終優勝者は…
Yes! The final winner is...
自分で言うのも何なんですが…
It's a bit awkward to say it myself, but...
ねねねでーす！やったー！
It's Nene-ne! Yay!
ねねがホロライブ一のオシャレ魔女！
Nene is hololive's number one Fashionable Witch!
さすが！イエーイ！
As expected! Yay!
え、最後に三人で、もう一回みんなと踊りたいな、って思ったんだけど…
Um, finally, I thought I'd like to dance with everyone one more time as a trio...
おわ？じゃあ、あのさ…
Oh? Then, how about...
ちょうどラブとベリーがステージ行く時のポーズ、あれしようよ！
Let's do that pose Love and Berry do when they go on stage!
そうだね！じゃあ、オッケー、行こう！
Right! Then, okay, let's go!
よし！
Alright!
ストリートコートへ…
To the Street Court...
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
A B C D E 感じじゃない？
A B C D E feels good, right?
1 2 3 でジャンプしよう
Let's jump on 1, 2, 3
A B C D Everybody's all right
1 2 3 で Let's Go!
1, 2, 3, Let's Go!
声も出ないくらい
So much I can't even speak
胸に刺さった想い
Thoughts that pierced my heart
忘れかけたあの日のこと
The things from that day I'd almost forgotten
A B C D E 感じじゃない？
A B C D E feels good, right?
1 2 3 で踏み出そう
Let's step out on 1, 2, 3
A B C D いけるさ大丈夫
A B C D we can do it, it's okay
1 2 3 で OK!
1, 2, 3, OK!
うわああああ！やったー！
Whoaaa! We did it!
お疲れ様だ！おいでこっち！
Good job! Come over here!
疲れたー！広いね！
I'm tired! It's so spacious!
へーい！じゃあ、オシャレ魔女ヴィーナス出航！
Hey! Then, Oshare Majo Venus, setting sail!
はい！出航！
Yes! Setting sail!
あ！上がってきたー！
Ah! It's going up!
すごい！めっちゃ綺麗！
Amazing! It's so beautiful!
とばないで！とばないで！
Don't jump! Don't jump!
おちちゃう、おちちゃう！あ、まってまって！
You'll fall, you'll fall! Ah, wait, wait!
ちょっと！
Hey!
まって！
Wait!
ちょっとやめて！あ、やめて！
Wait, stop it! Ah, stop!
わらわないで、わらわないで！あ、こわい！
Don't laugh! Don't laugh! Ah, I'm scared!
ね、みて、カブトムシね、くちついてんの。
Look, the beetle has a mouth.
え、カブトムシ？
Eh? A beetle?
ほら、たらこくちびるでしょ？
Look, those are big lips, right?
かわいい！にんげんみあふれるくち。
Cute! They look so human.
たべないでね、まつりちゃん。
Don't eat it, Matsuri-chan.
キスしちゃうかな。
I might kiss it.
キスしそうになって、そのついでにたべたくなっちゃうよね。
I'd start to kiss it, and then I'd want to eat it.
あのー、ちょっといい？ねぇねぇ。
Um, excuse me... Hey, hey.
このまえに、やっておかないといけないことがあるの。
There's something I have to do before this.
ちょっとつぎのためにきがえ...
I have to go change for the next part.
そうだった！
Oh, that's right!
ここらへんだと、やっぱりみんながみてる。
If I do it here, everyone will see me.
あー、なるほどね。ふたりはちょっとむこうむいてて。
Ah, I see. Then you two look over there.
まぁいいや、じゃあみてもいい、みてもいい...
Well, it's okay, you can watch, actually...
みてほしい。
I want you to watch.
みないで、みないで！
Don't look! Don't look!
やだー、ノーパン、ノーパンなんだけど！
Oh, no, I'm not wearing any underwear!
え、なに、ほんとだ！やばい！ほら、ぷりぷり！
Wait, really?! No way! Look, it's all jiggly!
ねえやばい、やだー、はやくきがえて！
Hey, stop it! Seriously, hurry up and change!
はやきがえ！
Quick change!
はやきがえ、はやきがえ！
Quick change, quick change!
これね、ねねだけきがえたのは...
The reason I'm the only one who changed...
ちょっとねねはつぎのところで、べつのことしないといけないから。
...is because I have to do something else in the next part.
あ、なるほどね。もうすぐみえてくるとおもうけど。
Ah, I see. I think we'll see it soon.
えーとね、あ、あそこ、あそこ！
Um, oh! There, there!
あそこか！よし、くだります。
Over there! Okay, we're going down.
くだりまーす！おりてる、おりてる！
Descending! We're going down!
じゃあねねはこのもりで、ムシキングしないといけないから。
Okay, Nene will be in this forest playing Mushiking.
ムシキングいいなー！
Mushiking is so nice!
そうなの、だからふたりはさきにいってて。
Exactly, so you two go ahead.
オッケー、まってる。まだあるから。
Okay, we'll be waiting. There's more to come.
オッケー、わすれないでね、きゅうけいしててください。
Okay, don't forget! Please take a break.
オッケー！たのしんできてね！
Okay! Have fun!
たのしんできてね！もうめっちゃたのしそう。
Have fun! It looks so fun.
じゃあまたあとでね！バイバイ！
See you later! Bye-bye!
バイバイ！たのしんで！
Bye-bye! Have fun!
ありがとう！はい、あがってー！
Thank you! Okay, up you go!
いくよー！はい、うぇーい！
Here we go! Up, up!
さぁ、つぎは、こちら！
Alright, next up is this!
甲虫王者ムシキング！
Mushiking: The King of Beetles!
こちらもセガさんに、こんかいかしていただきました。
Sega lent us this machine too!
と、いうわけでね、みんなといっしょに、もうこのリアルでね、
So, I want to be in this real...
ゲームセンターでムシキングをしてる当時の様子を再現したくて、
...game center atmosphere playing Mushiking with everyone like back in the day...
いまからなまはいしんで、やっていきたいとおもいます！
...so I'll do that in this live stream!
というわけで、ムシキング、やっていきましょう！
So, let's play Mushiking!
というわけでカードはこんかいも、ねねのカードをもってきました。
I brought my cards this time as well.
ストーリーモードがムシキングにはあって、アニメとはまたちょっとちがうないようでね、
Mushiking has a Story Mode, which is a bit different from the anime.
やってるので、いっしょにルールせつめいもしながら、ストーリーモードでちょっとあそんでいきたいとおもいます。
So I'll play Story Mode while explaining the rules.
ムシキングはね、ムシカードと...
In Mushiking, there are Beetle Cards and...
あ、いまちょうどでてる！ムシカードとわざカードっていうのがあって、
Oh, it's showing right now! Beetle Cards and Skill Cards.
それをくみあわせて、あいてのムシとジャンケンでたたかう、みたいなかんじで、
You combine them and battle your opponent's beetle with Rock-Paper-Scissors.
かったほうがかち。ジャンケンにかったほうがかち、というゲームです。
Basically, whoever wins the Rock-Paper-Scissors wins.
いちおうわざごとにね、あいしょうがあったりはするんだけど、
There's also compatibility between different skills...
ま、それはね、きょうみがわいたかた、もっともっとしらべてみてください。
But if you're interested, please look it up.
とってもおくがふかいです。
It's very deep.
というわけで、えー...
Alright then...
おーりゃ！
Here we go!
ゲームをえらんでね。
Choose a game.
よーし、まずはさ、ひとりであそぶ。
Alright, first, let's play alone.
このさいしょのでき、これが、いちばんさいしょの、ね。
This 'First Deck' is the very first one.
やばい、おとが！おとがでかすぎる！
Whoa, the sound! The sound is so loud!
うん、やばい。
Yeah, it's great.
うまれたばかりのムシをそだてるんだ。
Raise a beetle that was just born.
あ、うまれたばかりのムシをそだてるんだ。
Ah, raise a beetle that was just born.
あ、やばい、こうふんしすぎてよだれでる。
Oh man, I'm so excited I'm drooling.
あ、これちょうひっさつわざ。まって、まって。
This is a Super Skill. Wait, wait.
あいてのちょうひっさつわざチョキだから、ねねはグーパンしたいんだよね。
The opponent's Super Skill is Scissors, so Nene wants to go with Rock.
カブトムシにでてきてもらおう。さあ、ねねがしょうかんする、ムシ！
Let's have the beetle come out. Now, the beetle Nene summons!
おいで！
Come on!
よしよしよし、なに、なににするとおもう？
Alright, alright. What, what do you think I'll pick?
ダゲキわざをおぼえたぞ！
Learned a Strike Skill!
ハサミわざをおぼえたぞ！
Learned a Squeeze Skill!
ナゲわざをおぼえたぞ！
Learned a Throw Skill!
さあ、こい！
Alright, come on!
ねねのムシ！
Nene's beetle!
やったー、エレファスゾウカブト！
Yay! Elephas Beetle!
やばい、うまれたてだからね、まだはねのいろがちゃんとしてない。
Oh man, it's just born, so its wing color isn't right yet.
かわいいー！
It's cute!
ねねの、ねねのとうじのさいきょうデッキだよ、これ。
This is Nene's strongest deck from back then.
すぐにたたかいます。
Let's battle right away!
ちょっと大きさ... 大きさが可愛そうすぎない？
Wait, the size... isn't the size difference too pitiful?
相手の超必殺技はチョキだから、ねねがグー出せばもうこれ勝ちってわけ。
The opponent's super move is Scissors, so if Nene uses Rock, it's a win.
やっただ！ 必殺技だ！ いくぞ！
I did it! Special move! Here I go!
ちょっともうバランス感が可愛そうすぎる。ねねの勝ちですよ、これ完全に。
The lack of balance is just too pitiful. This is completely Nene's win.
ちょっと可愛そう。あははは！
It's a bit pitiful. Ahahaha!
かっこいい！ 決まった！ しびれるぜ！
Cool! It's decided! It's electrifying!
あ、いい、これ2発でいけるかも。
Ah, good, maybe I can finish this in two hits.
こうやってね、あの主人公のポポくんって言うんだけど、ポポくんがじゃんけんのアシストをしてくれるの。
Like this, the protagonist, his name is Popo-kun, he assists you with Rock-Paper-Scissors.
優しい仕様なの。
It's a kind feature.
おいヒントどころか答えくれてるぞ。
Hey, he's giving the answer instead of a hint.
ちょ、デカすぎる。
Wait, it's too big.
おーいけ！
Oh, go!
やったね！ 羽が少し固まったよ！
You did it! The wings have hardened a bit!
2ばんめのてき
Second enemy
これみんなゲームの音さ、してる？ 聞こえる？
Everyone, is the game sound coming through? Can you hear it?
聞こえる？ このムシキングのゲームの音。
Can you hear it? This Mushiking game sound.
きたきたきたきた。あ、見て。
Here it comes. Ah, look.
ちょっと羽が... ちょっと羽が茶色くなる。
The wings... the wings turn a bit brown.
「さあ、気をつけて」ってことは、これチョキでくるの。
'Now, be careful' means it's coming with Scissors.
必殺技でするから、ねねはグー出して。
Since it's doing a special move, Nene uses Rock.
「気をつけて」の時は、相手の得意の技がくるんだよね、大体。
When it says 'Be careful', it usually means the opponent's signature move is coming.
このストーリーモードとかだと、もうこのポポのアシストでほぼ勝てる。
In this story mode, you can almost always win with Popo's assist.
必殺技をくらってフラフラしてる、チャンスだよ！
He's dizzy after taking a special move, here's your chance!
これね、もう一回出せるってことなんだと思う。
This means, I think, I can use it one more time.
フラフラしてるから、もう一回必殺技出したら最強だよ、みたいなアシストくれる。
Since he's dizzy, it gives an assist like 'It'll be the best if you use a special move again'.
いや、ポポさん最強だから。
Seriously, Popo-san is the strongest.
ポポ様だから。
He's Lord Popo.
やった！ 羽がもっと固まったよ！
Great! The wings have hardened even more!
うおー、こんな羽がヤバヤバの時に戦っちゃって。あ、
Whoa, fighting when the wings are in such a bad state. Oh,
3ばんめのてき
Third enemy
あ、ピオン、ピオン！
Ah, Peon, Peon!
アダーの赤い目の虫に見つかってしまった！ マルスか。
I was found by Adder's red-eyed beetle! Mars, huh?
この「アダーの赤い目」っていうのは、
This 'Adder's Red Eyes' thing...
あの、ポポの、まあ敵、森の中の妖精界の敵みたいなのがいるんだけど、
Popo has enemies, like enemies in the fairy world within the forest.
その人は、虫を、こう赤い目に改造して、
That person modifies the beetles to have red eyes...
改造して、赤い目にして、無理やり...
Modifies them, gives them red eyes, and forcibly...
あ、このおじさん、このおじさん。このおじさんに戦わせようとしてんの。
Ah, this old man, this old man. He's trying to make them fight.
これを倒して、赤い目の、そのアダーコレクションって言うんだけど、
By defeating this, the red-eyed... it's called the Adder Collection...
この赤い目の虫から解放してあげよう、みたいなのをする。
We do something like 'Let's liberate them from being red-eyed beetles'.
解放している今。
I'm liberating it right now.
あ、しまった！ やばい！
Ah, shoot! Oh no!
あ、でも必殺技ではないか。
Ah, but it wasn't a special move.
これこれ！ デーン！
This is it! Da-da-da!
あ、この音、この音。
Ah, this sound, this sound.
フフフ、もう後がないぞ！
Hehe, there's no turning back now!
えー、これは必殺技いっちゃうから。
Eh, I'm going for the special move then.
「後がないぞ」って言って必殺技出すしかないぞ、って今アシストもらってる。
He says 'There's no turning back,' giving me the assist to use a special move.
これ！ この音！
This! This sound!
羽が固まった！ 今だ、今こそ決め手が決まったよ！
The wings have hardened! Now, the finishing blow has landed!
いっぱい触っておかないと。
Got to touch it a lot.
さいごのてき
Final enemy
4回戦。
4th round.
あ、ブルマイ！ ブルマイスターツヤクワガタじゃんこれ。
Ah, Blue Master! It's a Blue Master Stag Beetle.
あ、やばい。超必殺技がマックスに。
Ah, oh no. The super move is at max.
サイズ感的には、
In terms of size...
僕たちを呼んでる、ってことはグー出そうとしてパー出そうとしてチョキ。
They're calling us, which means he's trying Rock, then Paper, then Scissors.
きた、ローリングクラッチホールド！
Here it is, Rolling Clutch Hold!
痛そうだなって思ってたんだよね、ずっと。
I've always thought that looks painful.
あ、でもあんまり入らない。さすがにちょっと強い。
Ah, but it doesn't do much damage. As expected, he's a bit strong.
あ、やばい、負けちゃう。
Ah, oh no, I'm going to lose.
あ、いくか。
Ah, shall I go for it?
メキメキメキ。すごい音。
Crack-crack-crack. What a sound.
うわー、これ運だな。「もう諦めろ」の時は運だけど、
Whoa, this is luck. When he says 'Give up already', it's luck, but...
あ、やばい、やばい、やばい！
Ah, oh no, oh no, oh no!
これね、技カードにも2パターンあって、なんか攻撃する技と、
There are two types of technique cards: ones for attacking and...
なんか他の技とか、虫へのアシストみたいのをするカードも。
cards that give other techniques or assists to the beetles.
あ、待って、やべ、やべ、やべ。消された。
Ah, wait, shoot, shoot, shoot. It got erased.
やばい、やばい、やばい。
Oh no, oh no, oh no.
あ、まずい。
Ah, this is bad.
あ、そっか。
Ah, I see.
あ！ちょっとエレファス！
Ah! Hey, Elephas!
だめだよ、強くなってる。あ、やばい負けちゃった。
No way, it's gotten stronger. Ah, oh no, I lost.
きみは 負けてしまった
You have lost.
きみは負けてしまった。
ともだちと たいせんして うでを みがくんだ
Battle with your friends to hone your skills.
友達と対戦して腕を磨くんだ。
あ、す、ぼくこれ持ってます。
Oh, I have this.
みんなの カードが つかえるよ
You can use everyone's cards.
みんなのカードが使えるよ。
これね、虫の育成もできるし。
With this, you can also raise insects.
こうたい するときは ムシキングカードを わすれないでね
Don't forget your Mushiking cards when you change.
次のお友達に代わる時はムシキングカードを忘れないでね。
Don't forget your Mushiking cards when you change to the next friend.
次のお友達いないんで。
I don't have a next friend.
いないんで。一人なんで。
I don't have one. Because I'm alone.
ゲームを えらんでね
Please choose a game.
ゲームを選んでね。
切な... えっと、これね。
How sad... um, this one.
一人で遊ぶ。改造甲虫と戦うんだ。
Play alone. You'll fight against modified beetles.
この改造甲虫のところのストーリーを見ると、アダーコレクションのところが分かるんで。
If you watch the story for these modified beetles, you'll understand about the Adder Collection.
さいしょの てき
The first opponent.
ほう、おもしろいものを見せてやろう。
Ho, let me show you something interesting.
どうやってこの改造の虫が生まれてきているか、みたいな。
Like, how these modified insects are born.
さあ、きみのムシカードをスキャンして。
Now, scan your insect card.
昔はさ、ここがかわいそうすぎて...
In the past, this part was just too sad...
ムシカードがないときはボタンを押してね。
Press the button if you don't have an insect card.
さあ、さあ、さあ、ねねの、ねねのムシ君。
Come on, come on, come on, Nene's, Nene's insect friend.
ま、でも相手の必殺技パーだからね。
Well, but the opponent's special move is Paper.
ねねはチョキ勝ち、チョキ勝ちしていきたいところではある。
Nene wants to win with Scissors, win with Scissors.
イエーイ！来た！
Yay! It's here!
ギラファ！ギラファノコギリクワガタ！
Giraffa! Giraffa stag beetle!
すごい、完璧だ！
Amazing, perfect!
はいはいはいはい。
Right, right, right, right.
相手の必殺技にも注意してね。
Pay attention to the opponent's special moves too.
よしよしよし、相手の必殺技注意。完遂、完遂、あ。
Alright, alright, alright, watch out for the opponent's special move. Complete it, complete it, ah.
あ、ほら、見て。後ろでさ。
Ah, look, look. In the background.
最初は必殺技でくるよ！気をつけて！
They'll start with a special move! Watch out!
さいしょは ひっさつわざで くるよ！ きをつけて！
最初は必殺技でくるからパーでチョキ...
They'll start with a special move, so Paper, then Scissors...
やった、必殺技だ！
Alright, it's a special move!
いいの？ブルロック出ちゃっていいの？
Is it okay? Is it okay to use Bull Lock?
スキャナーの上に置くのが、通のやり方だから。
Placing it on top of the scanner is the way experts do it.
決まった、完璧だ！
It's decided, perfect!
戻さないの、ケースに。
I don't put it back in the case.
あ、何をしているんだ？あれは一体何なんだ？
Ah, what are you doing? What on earth is that?
あ、やばい、ポポのアシストが足りない。
Ah, oh no, Popo's assist isn't enough.
教えてやろう。改造昆虫、恐怖の改造人間だ！
I'll tell you. Modified insects, terrifying modified humans!
あいこの ときは さっきと おなじわざで くるよ
When it's a tie, they'll use the same move as before.
あ、やばい、やばい、生まれてくる。こうやって改造して...
Ah, oh no, oh no, it's being born. Modifying it like this...
無理やり戦わせてんの. 酷すぎん？
And forcing it to fight. Isn't that too cruel?
やった、必殺技だ！
Alright, it's a special move!
いいの？
Is it okay?
でもムシキングのカードには、アダーコレクションっていうのもあって。
But in the Mushiking cards, there's also the Adder Collection.
その赤い目をこっち側にして戦うこともできる。
You can also fight with that red eye on this side.
見て、超かっこいい。
Look, so cool.
決まった、完璧だ！
It's decided, perfect!
さなぎに、なんてことだ... やめさせるんだ。
To a pupa, how awful... stop this.
やばい、もうさなぎから大分帰っちゃって...
Oh no, it's already changed quite a bit from a pupa...
２ばんめの てき
The second opponent.
すぐに分からせてやろう。
I'll make you understand soon.
アルキデスオオヒラタクワガタ！
Alcides stag beetle!
もうびちびちなんだから。このフレームいっぱいに名前書いてある。
It's so crowded. Its name is written all over the frame.
やばい、もうほぼ生まれてんだよね。見えてる見えてる。
Oh no, it's almost born. I can see it, I can see it.
さいしょは きをつけて
Watch out at the start.
最初は気をつけて、ってことは、必殺技出てくるからパー。
'Watch out at the start' means a special move is coming, so Paper.
やった、必殺技だ！
Alright, it's a special move!
ローリングドライバーね！ドンドンドンドンドンドン。
Rolling Driver! Boom boom boom boom boom boom.
これね、みんな大好きローリングドライバー。
This is everyone's favorite, Rolling Driver.
決まった、完璧だ！
It's decided, perfect!
ついに完成の時が来た！最強のパラワンオオヒラタじゃ！
The time for completion has finally come! It's the strongest Palawan stag beetle!
やばい！
Oh no!
まだうまく動けないんだ！隊長に！
It still can't move well! To the Captain!
そう、でもまだうまく動けないときにさっきねねと戦わせちゃった。
Right, but it was forced to fight Nene earlier when it couldn't move well yet.
あいこの ときは ヒントを おもいだして！
When it's a tie, remember the hint!
あいこのときはヒントを思い出して！あいこのときはもう一回出してこようとするからグー。
When it's a tie, remember the hint! When it's a tie, it tries to use the same move again, so Rock.
やった、必殺技だ！
Alright, it's a special move!
百烈拳行きます！
Here comes the Hundred Crack Fist!
決まった、完璧だ！
It's decided, perfect!
ヒュー！え、なんかさ、今出した技をねねに勝ちにくるよ。
Whew! Oh, like, it's going to try and beat Nene with the move she just used.
グーに勝ちに来るからパーでチョキ。
Since it's coming to beat Rock, Paper, then Scissors.
やった、必殺技だ！
Alright, it's a special move!
なんかね、ねねがこの、このデッキで行くわ、ってブラザーに見せたらさ...
You know, when Nene showed this deck to her brother and said she was going with it...
「甘いな」って言われた。
He told me, 'How naive'.
だめなんだよね、そういうパワーでごり押ししようとしたら。
It's no good if you just try to push through with power like that.
サポートの技入れないとダメだよ、って言われた。なんか、めっちゃ悔しかったわ。
He told me, 'You have to include support moves'. I was so frustrated.
ここでは羽が固まらんようじゃな。
The wings won't harden here, it seems.
いい、いい、だめ、ついてこい！
Good, good, no, come with me!
わ、なんておじさんだ。
Wow, what a guy.
３ばんめの てき
The third opponent.
パラワンオオヒラタの羽が固まるまで時間を稼ぐんじゃ。
Stall for time until the Palawan stag beetle's wings harden.
おいリッキー、リッキーに時間稼がそうとすんなよ。
Hey, Ricky. Don't try to make Ricky stall for time.
最強これ、もうボーイズみんなの憧れなんだけど。
This is the strongest, it's what all the boys admire.
チョキを出したいというのが分かってるから、向こうはグーを出してくるからねねはパー。
Because it knows I want to use Scissors, it'll use Rock, so Nene uses Paper.
ぼくたちの てを よんでいる
They are reading our moves.
やった、必烈だ！
Alright, it's a special move!
うわー、最強や。
Wow, it's the strongest.
リッキーとギラファの戦いめっちゃ熱くない？
Isn't the battle between Ricky and Giraffa super intense?
ぼくたちの てを よんでいる
They are reading our moves.
手を見ている、手を読んでいる、もう一回パー。
It's watching the moves, it's reading them. Paper again.
リッキーブルー、さっさと片付けろ！
Ricky Blue, finish it quickly!
きたパーだからチョキ。
It's using Paper, so Scissors.
やった、必殺技だ！
Alright, it's a special move!
できた！
I did it!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
これのために、この超必殺技合わせしてんだよ！
I set up this super special move combo just for this!
ムシキングってこういうゲーム！　見ててくださいよ！
This is what Mushiking is all about! Watch this!
もうこれが楽しくて、これが楽しくて！
Oh, this is so fun, so fun!
ハネがカタつく前にショウをみつけなきゃ。急ごう！
Must find Sho before my wings stiffen. Let's hurry!
ねねの行きつけだったのは...
Nene's regular spot was...
ジャスコとイトーヨーカドー。いろんな各地を回って全然並んでない所を探す...
Jusco and Ito-Yokado. I'd go to various places looking for spots with no lines...
空気が変だ！　僕たちの手も震えている！
The air feels strange! Our hands are shaking too!
あ〜グー、チョキで、チョキにグーの最高スパ...
Ah, rock, scissors... the best super move of rock against scissors...
あ、さらに読まれている！
Ah, I'm being read even further!
読みが読まれてる！　あ、片付けろ言われてるｗ
My read is being read! Ah, he's telling me to clean it up lol.
あーまずい！
Ah, this is bad!
やばい、ノコギリクワガタとしてヒラタクワガタに負けられない！　わ、どうしよう！
Oh no, as a Prosopocoilus inclinatus, I can't lose to a Dorcus titanus! Wow, what should I do!
あ！え！まずいまずいまずい！やばい！あ、もっとヒートアップ！まずいまずい！
Ah! Eh! Bad bad bad! Oh no! Ah, heating up more! Bad bad!
あー絶対死んじゃった、やばい...
Ah, I'm definitely dead, oh no...
あぶっ！　やめて！　あぶねー！
Ah! Stop! That was close!
とどめをさしてやろう！
I'll deliver the finishing blow!
さすがに、さすがに超必殺技...
As expected, as expected, a super special move...
うわ、あぶなー！
Whoa, close!
まずい！　あー、ねねのキャラが！
Bad! Ah, Nene's character!
投げられちゃったよー！
I got thrown!
君は負けてしまった...
You have lost...
やだー！　勝ちの時、勝ちの時の画面も見たい！
No way! I want to see the victory screen too!
甲虫王者ムシキング　スーパーコレクションもよろしくね！
Also, check out Mushiking: The King of Beetles Super Collection!
よいしょ...　膝が、膝がもう力入れすぎちゃって...
Heave-ho... My knees, my knees are just... I put too much strength into them...
あ、次のお友達あ...　いない。いないいないいないわ。
Ah, the next friend... is not there. They're not there at all.
次のお友達がいる時はこうやってずっと画面見られてるし、交換できるカードがないかずっと見られてるの。あ〜。
When there's someone next in line, they're always staring at the screen and checking for cards to trade. Ahh.
え〜っと、という、これもう一回やってもいいんですか？
Umm, so, can I do this one more time?
お、もうゲーム始まっちゃったｗ
Oh, the game's already starting lol.
はい！ というわけで、今回は本当にありがとうございました！
Yes! So, thank you so much for today!
えーじゃあ最後にね、まあこの今広い、クソ広い森の中に来ていますので...
Well then, finally, since we're here in this vast, freaking vast forest right now...
ねねの、ムシキングの愛というか、虫への愛、ムシキングへの愛を、えー歌いたいと思います。
I'd like to sing Nene's love for Mushiking, or rather her love for bugs, her love for Mushiking.
というわけでね、ゲーム版ではなくアニメ版の、あのムシキングの曲、えー聞いてください。生きてこそ！
So, please listen to the Mushiking song from the anime, not the game version. Ikitekoso!
ママ私が生まれた日の
Mama, on the day I was born,
空はどんな色
what color was the sky?
パパ私が生まれた日の
Papa, on the day I was born,
気持ちはどうだった
how did you feel?
あれから言葉を覚えて
Since then, I've learned words,
私なりの愛も
and in my own way, love,
甘え方も体に染み込んだ
and how to be spoiled have soaked into my body.
生きてこそ
Just by living,
just by living,
今ここから始まる
everything starts from here now.
生きてこそ
Just by living,
just by living,
広がってまたつながる
we expand and connect again.
ママ私を初めて抱く
Mama, when you held me for the first time,
気持ちはどうだった
how did you feel?
パパ私が生まれた日の
Papa, on the day I was born,
嬉しかった
were you happy?
あれから奇跡を重ねて
Since then, accumulating miracles,
私なりの愛も
I want my own way of love,
出会いも育てていきたい
and encounters to grow too.
生きてこそ
Just by living,
just by living,
生きてこそ
Just being alive...
無限に羽ばたいてゆく夢
...is a dream that spreads its wings infinitely.
生きてこそ
Just being alive...
その根は深く太く強く
Its roots are deep, thick, and strong.
生きてこそ
Just being alive...
今ここから始まる
It starts from right here, right now.
生きてこそ
Just being alive...
広がってまた繋がる
It spreads out and connects again.
生きてこそ
Just being alive...
無限に羽ばたいてゆく夢
It's a dream that spreads its wings infinitely.
生きてこそ
Just being alive...
その根は深く太く強く
Its roots are deep, thick, and strong.
Yeah!
羽ばたいて
Spread your wings...
生きてこそ
Just being alive...
はい、というわけで、生きてこそでした。
All right, that was "Ikite Koso."
ねえ見て、なんか木漏れ日の民たちがさ
Look, the sunlight-through-the-trees people...
こう、舞っていく感じが、めっちゃ表現されてたでしょ、このキラキラで。
...the way they were dancing was really well expressed by this sparkle, wasn't it?
というわけで。
All right then.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho!
はい、上がってください。
Okay, take me up!
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
皆さんは今は、ムシキングの世界にいたんですけど、
Um, so everyone, just now you were in the world of Mushiking,
まあねねの大好きなムシ、
And, well, Nene's favorite bug...
ギラファノコギリクワガタ、
...the Giraffe Stag Beetle...
ヘラクレス、今日ちょっと準備はしてたんだけど、出す機会がなかったヘラクレス。
Hercules... I'd prepared it a bit for today, but I didn't get a chance to bring him out... Hercules.
いろんなムシたちへのねねの大好きな思いを込めて作った曲があるよね？
There's a song I made with all my love for various bugs, right?
というわけで、それをみんなで歌いたいと思います！
So, I'd like to sing that with everyone!
ステージがね、なんかその辺にあるんだけど...
The stage is, well, it's around there somewhere...
あ！あ！あ！そこ！あそこ！
Ah! Ah! Ah! There! Over there!
ハッピーギラファ！
Happy Giraffe!
ねねちのギラギラファンミーティングへようこそ！
Welcome to Nene-chi's Gira Gira Fan Meeting!
今日は一緒に踊ってくれる人たちが来てくれてるみたいなので、呼んでみたいと思います！
It seems like some people who will dance with me are here today, so I'd like to call them out!
それじゃ、いくやん！
All right then, let's go!
アミーゴ！カケーロ！ビバギラファ！！
Amigo! Kakero! Viva Giraffe!!
カブクワ！ギラギラ最高だね
Beetles! Sparkles are the best, aren't they?
カブクワ！
Beetles!
アモーレ！カブクワ　イェーイ！
Amore! Beetle, yeah!
カブクワ！クリクリおめめラブ
Beetles! Love those big round eyes!
カブクワ！
Beetles!
アモーレ！カブクワ　イェーイ！
Amore! Beetle, yeah!
会いに行こう
Let's go meet them.
ダンスはムチュムチュ
Dance with passion.
飛んでシュビドゥバ　メロメロ
Fly away, shoo-bee-doo-bah, captivated.
みんな集まれ　ゾロゾロ
Everyone gather round, one by one.
ほらチューチューチュー　バヤバヤパパ
Look, chu chu chu, baya baya papa!
ギラギラパ！ギラギラパ！
Gira Gira Pa! Gira Gira Pa!
めちゃめちゃなら元気におはよう
If you're super energetic, say good morning!
Let's Go! カブクワパレード
Let's Go! Beetle Parade!
おしゃれなんてそっちのけ出かけよう
Forget about fashion, let's head out!
いってらっしゃい！
Off you go!
いってきまーす！
I'm heading out!
エレファス！コーカサス！ヘラクレス！
Elephas! Caucasus! Hercules!
ノコギリ！タランドゥス！
Nokogiri! Tarandus!
ホォー！
Whoo!
ファンミーティングが始まる
The fan meeting is starting!
出会いやー！
It's an encounter!
アミーゴ！カケーロ！ビバギラファ！！
Amigo! Kakero! Viva Giraffe!!
カブクワ！ギラギラ最大級
Beetles! Maximum sparkles!
カブクワ！
Beetles!
アモーレ！カブクワ　イェーイ！
Amore! Beetle, yeah!
カブクワ！テカテカつやつやの
Beetles! All shiny and glossy...
カブクワ！
Beetles!
アモーレ！カブクワ　イェーイ！
Amore! Beetle, yeah!
行進！お前が一番！
March on! You're number one!
むちゃむちゃ
Mucha mucha
可愛い
So cute
上腕二頭ペロペロ
Licking your biceps
みんな
Everyone
集まれ
Gather 'round
ゾロゾロ
In a long line
チュッ チュッ チュッ バヤバヤ
Chu chu chu Baya baya
皮剥きバナナと誘おう チュッ チュッ
Let's invite the peeled bananas, chu chu
たっぷりグラニュー加えましょう
Let's add plenty of granulated sugar
両手でクワッとわしづかみ
Grab it tight with both hands
揉んで揉んで揉んで揉んで
Knead, knead, knead, knead
交差した愛のジュレ
Crossing jellies of love
迷い中キミ専用ジュレ
A special jelly just for you in your hesitation
カブクワ欲しけりゃ塗りたくれ
If you want Kabukwa, smear it on
すごい！ お前らのおかげで、こんなにたくさんのカブクワたちが集まってきてるよ！
Amazing! Thanks to you guys, so many Kabukwas are gathering here!
みんなに拍手！
A round of applause for everyone!
そしてもちろんねねにも拍手ー！
And of course, a round of applause for Nene too!
あのビフレギウス
That Bifuregiusu
マルマルス
Marumarusu
虹色グランディス
Rainbow Grandis
みんなそれぞら愛してるけど
I love them all, but...
やっぱりキミが好き
I like you the best after all
ギラッパギラッパ
Girappa girappa
強くてかっこいい
Strong and cool
ギラギラファンタスティックな物語
In this glittering fantastic story
キミは宝物だよ
You are my treasure
ビバ！ギラファ！！
Viva! Giraffa!!
カブクワ ギラギラ最高だね
Kabukwa, glittering is the best
カブクワ あそれ カブクワ イェーイ
Kabukwa, asore, Kabukwa, yay
カブクワ クリクリおめめラブ
Kabukwa, love those big round eyes
カブクワ あそれ カブクワ イェーイ
Kabukwa, asore, Kabukwa, yay
チュッ チュッ チュッ バヤバヤ
Chu chu chu Baya baya
パヤパヤ パヤパヤ
Paya paya Paya paya
ギミチョコ！！
Gimme Choco!!
あたたたたたたたたーたーたーたったーたーたーたたったっずきゅん！
Atatatata... zukyun!
わたたたたたたたたたーたーたーたったーたーたーたたったっどきゅん！
Watatata... dokyun!
ずきゅん！ どきゅん！ ずきゅん！ どきゅん！ やだやだやだねばねばねば
Zukyun! Dokyun! Zukyun! Dokyun! No way, no way, no way, sticky sticky sticky
チェケラチョコレート チョコレート チョコチョチョいいかな？
Check it out chocolate, chocolate, is it okay, choco-cho-cho?
でもねちょっとウェイト ちょっと最近心配なんです
But wait a bit, I've been a bit worried lately
チェケラチョコレート チョコレート チョコチョチョいいかな？
Check it out chocolate, chocolate, is it okay, choco-cho-cho?
でもねちょっとウェイト ちょっと待ってチョコチョチョ
But wait a bit, wait a bit choco-cho-cho
あたたたたたたたたーたーたーたったーたーたーたたったっずきゅん！
Atatatata... zukyun!
わたたたたたたたたたーたーたーたったーたーたーたたったっどきゅん！
Watatata... dokyun!
ずきゅん！ どきゅん！ ずきゅん！ どきゅん！ まだまだまだねばねばねば
Zukyun! Dokyun! Zukyun! Dokyun! Not yet, not yet, not yet, sticky sticky sticky
チェケラチョコレート チョコレート チョコチョチョいいよね？
Check it out chocolate, chocolate, it's okay, choco-cho-cho, right?
でもねちょっとウェイト ちょっと最近心配なんです
But wait a bit, I've been a bit worried lately
チェケラチョコレート チョコレート チョコチョチョいいよね？
Check it out chocolate, chocolate, it's okay, choco-cho-cho, right?
でもねちょっとウェイト ちょっと待ってチョコチョチョ
But wait a bit, wait a bit choco-cho-cho
あたたたたたたたたたたた... ズッキュ！
Atatatatatatata... Zukkyu!
Atatatatatatatata... Zukkyu!
ズッキュ！ズッキュ！ズッキュ！ズッキュ！
Zukkyu! Zukkyu! Zukkyu! Zukkyu!
やだやだやだやだ ネバネバネバ！
No no no no, sticky sticky sticky!
ヤダいちゃっちゃハートちょい一杯がんばったんです
I worked hard on this heart that says "no way!"
だからちょっとハートちょっとだけお願いなんです
So please, just a little bit of your heart!
早くチョコレート チョコレート ちょっちょっちょーだい
Hurry up and give me chocolate, chocolate, cho-cho-cho!
よこせチョコレート チョコレート ピー！
Hand over the chocolate, chocolate, pee!
チェケラチョコレート チョコレート ちょっちょっちょーいいでしょ
Check it out, chocolate, chocolate, it's good, right?
だよねちょっちょグッド 超ハッピーでがんばっちゃうんです
Right? A little good, super happy, I'll do my best!
だからチョコレート チョコレート ちょっちょっちょーいいでしょ
So chocolate, chocolate, it's good, right?
だよねちょっとだけ ちょっとだけ食べちゃお
Right? Just a little, just a little, let's eat it!
あたたたたたたたたたたた... ズッキュ！
Atatatatatatatata... Zukkyu!
ズッキュ！ズッキュ！ズッキュ！ズッキュ！ズッキュ！ズッキュ！
Zukkyu! Zukkyu! Zukkyu! Zukkyu! Zukkyu! Zukkyu!
ヘイヘイヘイ！
Hey hey hey!
えー、ピーカブーのポーズしてみたいと思います！
Uh, I'd like to try the Peek-a-boo pose!
はーい！
Okay!
せーの！まずは私達から！
One, two! First, from us!
もうやったじゃん、だってさっき！
But we already did it earlier!
ピー、ピー、ピー、ピー、ピー！
Pee, pee, pee, pee, pee!
お前、お前、そっち、そっち！
You, you! Over there, over there!
俺が撮る！ピー、ピー、ピー...
I'll take the photo! Pee, pee, pee...
隠れてる！ケ、ケ、ケ、ケ、ケ！
You're hiding! Ke, ke, ke, ke, ke!
ケ！あ、ボ、ボ、ボ！ボト、ボト！OK OK OK！
Ke! Ah, bo, bo, bo! Boto, boto! OK OK OK!
ビー、ビー、ビー、ビー！
Bee, bee, bee, bee!
頑張れビー！うぅ〜〜！
Do your best, Bee! Uuuuu!
あ、できてなくない？
Ah, isn't it failing?
はい！というわけで、私達ピーカブーでした！
Yes! So, that was us, Peek-a-boo!
イェーイ！ありがとう！みんなキミチョコ一緒にやってくれてありがとね！
Yay! Thank you! Everyone, thank you for doing Kimi Choco with us!
楽しかったー！めっちゃ疲れたよね！
That was fun! We're so tired, right?
お疲れ様でしたー！良かった！
Good job everyone! It was great!
というわけで、ねねはまだあるんで、頑張って！二人は？
So, Nene still has more, so good luck! What about you two?
解散！しれっ！解散！解散！
Dismissed! Sneak off! Dismissed! Dismissed!
まつり行こ、はちゃ、はちゃ、はちゃ、はちゃ！
Matsuri, let's go! Ha-cha, ha-cha, ha-cha, ha-cha!
待って、待って！行くよ、行くよ、行くよ！
Wait, wait! We're going, we're going, we're going!
ああああああ！
Aaaaaaaaa!
はい、ありがとうございました。次に行きます。
Yes, thank you very much. I'll move on to the next part.
はい。あの、大変盛り上がっているところ恐縮なのですが、
Yes. Um, I'm sorry to interrupt while things are so lively, but...
ねねからお知らせをさせてくださーい！お知らせこちらです！ドーン！
Please let Nene make an announcement! Here it is! Ta-da!
お誕生日を記念したグッズが発売されます！イェーイ！
Merchandise commemorating my birthday will be released! Yay!
えーもう見て丸わかりの通り、えー、西沢5㍉先生にビジュアルを描いてもらいました！
As you can see, the visuals were drawn by Nishizawa 5mm-sensei!
今回は、まあお風呂とかお風呂上がりとかそういう感じのイメージで、あの、コンセプトで作っております。
This time, the concept is based on an image of taking a bath or being fresh out of the bath.
紹介していきます。まずは、こちら！
I'll introduce them. First, this one!
えー、西沢5㍉先生の描いてくれたお写真。B2タペストリーです！
The illustration drawn by Nishizawa 5mm-sensei. It's a B2 Tapestry!
なんかこうお風呂上がりにね、ちょっと飲み物なんか飲んじゃって、プハーって、プハーってしてる感じの、
It's like having a drink after a bath and going "Phaa...", you know, that feeling...
ねねのB2タペストリー！これ絶対に、絶対に大きいので、絶対にサイズ感が大きいので、
The Nene B2 Tapestry! This is definitely, definitely big, the size is really large,
皆さんぜひ手に入れてください！そして次が、こちら！
So everyone, please get one! And next is this!
え、缶バッジです！最近、あの、痛バとか作ってくれる人が、あの、X見てて多くて、
Uh, tin badges! Recently, I've seen many people making things like ita-bags on X,
なんか缶バッジもっと増えたらいいなと思って缶バッジにしました！
So I thought it would be great to have more badges, and I made these!
イラストはね、いつも可愛い、あの、ファンアート描いてくれてる山猫先生に描いていただきました。ありがとう！
The illustrations were drawn by Yamaneko-sensei, who always draws cute fanart. Thank you!
え、そして続きましては、こちら！
And moving on, here's this!
え、ビールジョッキ！まあビールジョッキって書いてあるんだけど、お風呂上がりにプハーっとね、
A beer mug! Well, it's called a beer mug, but you can go "Phaa!" after a bath,
一杯飲み物をいただけちゃう、えー、ビールジョッキが出ます！
And enjoy a drink. A beer mug will be released!
ねねの配信でご飯時の時が多いので、これでみんなで一緒にご飯時にプハーしましょう！
Nene's streams are often during dinner time, so let's all go "Phaa!" together with this!
そして、なんかお風呂っぽいの一つ欲しいなと思って、こちら！
And, I wanted something that felt bath-like, so here's this!
なんかあのお風呂行った時に、外のお風呂に行った時に、あの、鍵かける時に使うやつ、
You know, when you go to a public bath, that thing you use when you lock the locker...
あの、鍵のやつで、女、これで頭を縛り上がりますね、これで。これでまとめ上がりまして、
That key thing. For women, you can tie your hair with this. It'll keep it tied up,
あの、鍵を無くさないのと同時に髪をまとめ上がります、これで。え、それのキーホルダー！
So you don't lose the key, and you can tie your hair at the same time. It's a keychain of that!
なんかちょっとお湯っぽい感じのねねが描いてあって、色はね、この色にしてあります。
It has an illustration of Nene looking like she's in hot water, and the color is this color.
そして次は、こちら！
And next is this!
え、ボイス！シチュエーションボイス「ねねちのお風呂ボイス」
Voice! Situation voice: "Nenechi's Bath Voice."
というわけでね、一緒に入ってるか入ってないかは、みんなの耳で...
So, whether we're in the bath together or not, you'll have to hear with your own ears...
確かめてください。
Please check it out.
そして今回も、えー、フルセットの購入特典があります。こちら！
And this time too, there's a purchase bonus
for the full set. Here it is!
誕生日記念フルセット
Birthday Commemoration Full Set
えー、フルセットを買っていただきますと、え、ポストカードと特典のボイスがついてきます。こちら！
Um, if you buy the full set, it comes with a
postcard and a bonus voice. Here!
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
購入特典はね、見てみんな。あの、お顔がね、ちょっともう酔っ払っちゃっちゃっぴーみたいな感じの顔になってるポストカードと、
The purchase bonus, look everyone.
On this postcard, my face looks a bit like
"I'm already drunk-appy," and...
えー、直筆サイン＆箔押しの複製メッセージ入りポストカード！
...a postcard with a handwritten signature
and a foil-stamped replicated message!
え、そして、え、お風呂上がりにいっぱい喉が渇いて飲んじゃって、「あ、酔っ払っちゃった〜」みたいなボイスがついてきまーす。
And, um, a voice pack like "Ah, I got drunk~"
from drinking a lot because I was thirsty after
a bath.
あの、あの、ぜひ、ぜひぜひぜひ、あの、よろしくお願いします。ありがとうございます。
Um, um, please, please please please, um,
look forward to it. Thank you very much.
え、そしてですね、今回、あの、本当はね、ねぽらぼ全員呼びたかったんですけど、ま、タイミングとかね、体調のこともありまして、ラミィが来れなかったんですよ。
And also, this time, um, to be honest, I
wanted to invite all of NePolabo, but due to
timing and health issues, Lamy couldn't come.
でも、ラミィに「ねぇ、あとなんか、なんか頂戴」って言ったら、あの、お手紙をくれたので、ラミィのお手紙、ねねまだ見てないので、あの、ここで晒していきたいと思います。
But when I asked Lamy, "Hey, give me
something else," she gave me a letter.
Nene hasn't seen it yet, so I'd like to share it
here.
これです！
Here it is!
ハッピーバースデー！いつも周りの人を笑顔に、そして元気をくれるねねかが大好きだよ！
Happy birthday! I love Nenekka, who always
makes everyone around her smile and gives
them energy!
ポンコツなところも、アイドルに全力なところも、全部大好き！ちゅきちゅきちゅき！
I love everything about you, from your ditzy
side to how you give your all as an idol!
Love, love, love you!
あ、これ二人で歌ってみたの時のやつですね。ん〜
Ah, this is from when the two of us did a
'tried singing' cover. Mmm.
う、ラミィさん、いい、いいわ〜。なんかいいじゃないの。なんか。これはちょっと後で現像して額に入れることにします。
Uhh, Lamy-san, this is nice, so nice. It's just
good. I'll develop this later and put it in a
frame.
というわけで、今日はタイミング的に、えー、ラミィはいなくて。そして、おまるは今日、あの、無事に戻ってきたということで、お祝いも込めて、
So, because of the timing, Lamy isn't here
today. And since Omaru successfully returned
today, to celebrate that as well,
最後は、えっと、ねぽぼ、3人で歌っていきたいと思います！
Lastly, um, the three of us, NePoBo, will sing
together!
それでは最後、レッツゴー！いいだよー！
Now for the last part, let's go! It's okay!
U&I
作詞：平沢 唯　作曲・編曲：前澤 寛之
Lyrics: Hirasawa Yui / Music: Maezawa Hiroyuki
君がいないと　何もできないよ
I can't do anything without you
君のご飯が食べたいよ
I want to eat your cooking
もし君が帰ってきたら　とびきりの笑顔で
If you were to come back, with a huge smile
抱きつくよ
I'd give you a big hug
君がいないと　謝れないよ
I can't apologize without you
君の声が聞きたいよ
I want to hear your voice
君の笑顔が見れれば
If I can see your smile
それだけでいいんだよ
That's all I need
君がそばにいるだけで
Just having you by my side
いつも勇気もらってた
Always gave me courage
いつまでも一緒にいたい
I want to be with you forever
この気持ちを伝えたいよ
I want to tell you how I feel
晴れの日も　雨の日も
On sunny days, and on rainy days
君はそばにいてくれた
You were there by my side
目を閉じれば君の笑顔
When I close my eyes, your smile
輝いてる
Is shining
君がいないと　何もわからないよ
I don't understand anything without you
砂糖と醤油はどこだっけ
Where were the sugar and soy sauce again?
もし君が帰ってきたら　びっくりさせようと
If you were to come back, I'd try to surprise
you
思ってたのにな
Is what I was thinking
君についつい甘えちゃうよ
I end up depending on you
君が優しすぎるから
Because you're just too kind
君にもらってばかりで
I'm always receiving from you
何もあげられてないよ
And haven't been able to give anything back
君がそばにいることを
That you being by my side
当たり前に思ってた
Is something I took for granted
こんな日々が　ずっとずっと
That days like these, on and on
続くんだと思ってたよ
Would just continue, I thought
ごめん　今は気づいたよ
Sorry, now I finally realize
...言いたいよ　当たり前じゃないことに
...I want to say it, for things that aren't taken for granted.
まずは君に　伝えなくちゃ　ありがとう
First of all, I have to tell you: thank you.
ありがとう！届いてるかー！
Thank you! Can you hear me?!
聴こえてますかー！
Can you hear me?!
ヘイ！ヘイ！ヘイ！ヘイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ちゃんと元気でやってまーす！
I'm doing great!
君の胸に　届くかな
I wonder if it will reach your heart.
今は自信ないけれど
I don't have much confidence right now, but...
笑わないで　ちゃんと聴いて
Please don't laugh, just listen properly.
想いを歌に込めたから
Because I put my feelings into the song.
ありったけの　ありがとう
All the "thank yous" I have.
歌に乗せて　届けたい
I want to send them through this song.
この気持ちは　ずっとずっと
This feeling, forever and ever,
忘れないよ　想いよ
I won't forget. Oh, these feelings.
想いよ...
These feelings...
届けー！
Reach them!
ヘイ！ヘイ！ヘイ！ヘイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
フッフッフー！
Hoo hoo hoo!
ジャンジャンジャンジャーン！
Jyan jyan jyan jyan!
もう一回！
One more time!
ジャンジャンジャンジャーン！
Jyan jyan jyan jyan!